Rafael Bertoldi Rossi

+55 47 99165-5338 · raffarossi@hotmail.com · linkedin.com/rbrossi

Data Analyst with +3 years of experience in developing, evaluating and deploying Machine Learning models, building dashboards, analyzing stock market data and developing trading strategies.

Experience in Python and Data Science libraries like Pandas, scikit-learn, Keras, Pytorch and Plotly.

Experience with designing, implementing, and maintaining Azure environments with the best DevOps practices.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst May 2021 – Present

Asa Investments, Rio de Janeiro, RJ

- Design, implement and maintain Asa's dashboard with Python, Django, PostgreSQL and Plotly on Azure
- Improve economic and fundamental indicators to provide insights to the equity team
- Design and implement backtest framework to analyze long and short and momentum trading strategies
- Analyze and predict economic and fundamental data from Bloomberg Terminal
- Gathering alternative data through webscrapping, APIs and government datasets
- Implement CI/CD, data pipelines and automation scripts on Azure and Github Actions

Data Analyst Oct 2020 – May 2021

Ambev Tech, Blumenau, SC

- Build and evaluate Machine Learning algorithms like XGBoost, LightGBM and Decision Trees to improve logistic and warehouse operations
- Maintain a web platform to manage and deploy into production environment more than 100 ML models
- Create new features to improve Machine Learning models and evaluate with SHAP
- Meet the final client to understand business needs and perform requirements gathering

DevOps Engineer Nov 2019 – Oct 2020

Ambev Tech, Blumenau, SC

- Architect and deploy solutions in Azure to lower the cost of operations
- Ensure the best DevOps practices with CI/CD automations with Github Actions
- Help dev teams with API Management, Express Route, Application Gateway, Kubernetes Services, Log Analytics, Azure Monitor and Datadog
- Create and optimize pipelines in Azure DevOps and ensure integration with SonarQube, Nexus, GitLab and Github

Infrastructure Analyst Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

Ambev Tech, Blumenau, SC

- Monitor and analyze AB Inbev infrastructure with Zabbix
- Create Powershell automations to improve Windows and Linux servers maintenance
- Execute and optimize daily backup routines with Powershell and Python scripts

Technical Support Coordinator

Sep 2014 - Apr 2018

Unifique Telecomunicações, Timbó, SC

- Responsible for managing technical support 27 employees
- Ensure high quality service and effective troubleshooting
- Teach and train new employees to be able to solve high complexity problems
- Resume evaluation and hiring new analysts

Unifique Telecomunicações, Timbó, SC

- Troubleshoot interconnections (VLAN, MPLS, EOIP) and clients with dedicated access ensuring high quality Internet access Fiber, Cable and Radio connections
- Provide technical support via phone and e-mail
- Configure e-mail clients, DNS and new domain names
- Monitor and analyze all the ISP backbone and infrastructure with Zabbix, Nagios, PRTG and Cacti

Intern May 2012 – Dec 2012

RT Informática, Indaial, SC

• Responsible for computer repair, virus removal, install and update softwares, format hard drives, install OS and set-up routers, switches and GPUs

EDUCATION

Specialization, Data Science

Universidade Regional de Blumenau - FURB Oct 2019 - May 2022

Bachelor, Computer Science

Universidade Regional de Blumenau - FURB 2014 – 2019